KONSTANTIN CHERNYSHEV

@ kdchernyshev+job@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/kdchernvshev

Groningen, Netherlands github.com/k4black

k4black.github.io



EXPERIENCE

Python Course Manager, Lecturer **Yandex School of Data Analysis**, Russia

📋 Jan 2021 - Present

- Managed a team of 9 people, planning, review, tech supervision;
- Conducted lectures on 'Packages and Modules', 'C-bindings';
- Boosted assignment-checking system (e.g 6x acceleration). (Management) (Python) (Teaching) (Docker) (PyTest) (Gitlab-CI) (Github-Actions)

Data Scientist

📋 Jan 2022

@EPAM Systems, Serbia

- Aug 2022

- Trained an unsupervised model for support ticket trends over time;
- Implemented a processing team predictive model, improving ticket processing efficiency by ~10s seconds per ticket for 100k t./year. (Python) (FastText) (SkLearn) (PyTorch) (PyTest) (Docker)

Research Engineer, Project Manager

- Jan 2022

Gorky AI, Russia

- Managed 2-4 developers per project, liaising with clients;
- Introduced Align flow, CI/CD, code reviews, improved teamwork;
- Adapted Voice Conversion model for Russian, close to real speech;
- Developed a highly-loaded 'roads quality' model on mobile data;
- Designed and developed a solution for scanned document analysis, trained a high mAP (~0.94) CV model for tables, pics, and stamps. (Python) (PyTorch) (HuggingFace) (SkLearn) (PyTest) (ONNX) (Docker) (Gitlab-Cl)

Research Intern

☐ Apr 2019 - Jan 2021

- *ØLATNA Lab at Higher School of Economics*, Russia
- Conducted research on Compressed Sensing with I1 and I0 norms, resulting in a near SoTA recovery algorithm with faster convergence;
- Created abstractive summarization model using knowledge graphs. (Statistics) (Python) (HuggingFace) (CoreNLP) (SkLearn) (SciPy)

EDUCATION

Master of Arts

Sep 2022

&EM "Language & Communication Technologies", EU

- Present

Join Degree: University of Groningen & Saarland University; GPA: 8.2/10 (ongoing); + TA at Language Technology Project.

Graduate student – two-year program **Yandex School of Data Analysis**, Russia

- Jul 2021

GPA: 8.9/10; + TA at Python Course.

Bachelor of Science

OHigher School of Economics, Russia

- Jul 2021

GPA: 9.1/10; + TA at Algorithms and Data Structures.

Courses and Certificates

- DL Optimization and Deployment using TensorFlow and TensorRT;
- Fundamentals of Accelerated Computing with CUDA Python:
- Intel Delta Courses (Delta 9, Delta 11).

SUMMARY

Passionate NLP Scientist with 4+ years of experience, love NLG and arduous tasks;

HSE, Russia graduate (BaSc with Honors), Erasmus Mundus LCT MsA till 2024. Has 5+ years of programming experience, 4+ vears of Data Science Research experience. Employed in Startups, Yandex DS School, EPAM, finished 8+ ML research projects.

SKILLS

Data Science

NLP DL ML NLU Summarization Graph Models (Speech) (CV) (RL)

Frameworks

HuggingFace PyTorch SkLearn Tensorflow NLPCore (TorchText)

Programming Languages

Python (C++) (CUDA) (GoLang) (Dart)

Development Tools

git Docker Neptune.ai GitLab-Cl GitHub-Actions ONNX TensorRT

Languages

Russian English German Serbian

PUBLICATIONS

• SLCT-1 at SemEval-2023 Task 10: Pre-training and Multi-task Learning for Sexism Detection and Classification [ACL-2023 workshop];

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Erasmus Mundus Scholarship 2022-2024:
- Placed 2nd at Moscow State hackathon "Digital Transformation 2021";
- Honours Bachelor's degree in CS;
- Largely improved Python course at YSDA, top-1 course by students' rating.

PERSONAL

Cheerful and sociable person, keen on slackline and juggling, love music making creativity and strive to master the guitar. Music Production (Juggling) (Slackline)